[
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?",
    "code": "print(\"Hello\", \"World\", sep=\"\\100\")",
    "answers": [
      "Hello100World",
      "Hello@World",
      "HellodWorld",
      "Hello World"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the program below if the user enters 11?",
    "code": "num=int(input(\"Enter a whole number: \"))\nif num%2 == 0:\n\tprint(\"Remainder of\",num,\"modulo 2 is 0\")\n\tprint(num,\"is an even number.\")\nelse:\n\tprint(\"Remainder of\",num,\"modulo 2 is 1\")\n\tprint(num,\"is an odd number.\")\nprint(\"Thank you\")",
    "answers": [
      "Remainder of 11 modulo 2 is 0\n11 is an even number\nThank you",
      "Remainder of 11 modulo 2 is 1\n11 is an even number\nThank you",
      "Remainder of 11 modulo 2 is 1\n11 is an odd number\nThank you",
      "Remainder of 11 modulo 2 is 0\n11 is an odd number\nThank you"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?",
    "code": "def x(n):\n\tif n == 0:\n\t\treturn 2\n\treturn x(n-1)**2\n\nprint(x(3))",
    "answers": [
      "8",
      "256",
      "6",
      "27"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which algorithm has a better time complexity when l = [1,2,3] and y = 2?",
    "code": "# Function 1\ndef f(l,y):\n\tfor i in l:\n\t\tif i == y:\n\t\t\tprint(f\"Found {y}\")\n\t\t\treturn\n\tprint(f\"{y} Not found\")\n# Function 2\ndef g(l,y):\n\tleft = 0\n\tright = len(l)- 1\n\twhile left <= right:\n\t\tmid = (left + right) // 2\n\t\tif y == l[mid]:\n\t\t\tprint(f\"Found {y}\")\n\t\t\treturn\n\t\telif y < l[mid]:\n\t\t\tright = mid - 1\n\t\telse:\n\t\t\tleft = mid + 1\n\tprint(f\"{y} Not found\")",
    "answers": [
      "f(l, y)",
      "g(l, y)",
      "both have the same complexity"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Which algorithm has a better Big O time complexity?",
    "code": "# Function 1\ndef f(l,y):\n\tfor i in l:\n\t\tif i == y:\n\t\t\tprint(f\"Found {y}\")\n\t\t\treturn\n\tprint(f\"{y} Not found\")\n# Function 2\ndef g(l,y):\n\tleft = 0\n\tright = len(l)- 1\n\twhile left <= right:\n\t\tmid = (left + right) // 2\n\t\tif y == l[mid]:\n\t\t\tprint(f\"Found {y}\")\n\t\t\treturn\n\t\telif y < l[mid]:\n\t\t\tright = mid - 1\n\t\telse:\n\t\t\tleft = mid + 1\n\tprint(f\"{y} Not found\")",
    "answers": [
      "f(l, y)",
      "g(l, y)",
      "both have the same complexity"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the time complexity of this algorithm?",
    "code": "def f(x):\n\tresult = []\n\tfor i in range(x):\n\t\tresult.append(i)\n\tfor j in range(x):\n\t\tresult[j] *= j\n\treturn result",
    "answers": [
      "O(2n)",
      "O(n^2)",
      "O(n)",
      "O(3n)"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?",
    "code": "# final.txt:\n#MA9LOOBA\ndef f(f):\n\tf.read(1)\n\tf.read(2)\n\treturn f.read(3)\nprint(f(open(\"final.txt\")))",
    "answers": [
      "MA9",
      "OBA",
      "Mohamed Salah Amine BENOUAR",
      "LOO"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Which data types are not allowed as keys in a dictionary?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": [
      "Lists and Floats",
      "Tuples and Integers",
      "Lists Only",
      "Lists and Sets"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?",
    "code": "l = []\ndef x(y):\n\tif y == -1:\n\t\treturn 7\n\tnum = y % 2\n\tl.append(x(y-1))\n\treturn num\nstring = \"Python\"\nx(3)\nprint(string[len(l)//2])",
    "answers": [
      "Error",
      "P",
      "t",
      "o"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the missing code that makes the program output 10?",
    "code": "merchants = {\n\t\"Abdelhakim\": {\n\t\t\"number of peaches\": len([[10]*3]*5),\n\t\t\"number of apples\": 26\n\t}\n}\nnumber_of_peaches = # Missing Code\nprint(number_of_peaches)",
    "answers": [
      "merchants[\"number of peaches\"] * 2",
      "merchants[\"Abdelhakim\"][\"number of apples\"] % 16",
      "merchants[\"Abdelhakim\"][\"number of peaches\"] ** 2",
      "merchants[\"Abdelhakim\"][\"number of apples\"] / 2.6"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  }
]